Mahdieh Zabihimayvan

Curriculum Vitae

Phone: (937) 397-8487 Email: Zabihimayvan.2@wright.edu,

Home page: http://zabihimayvan.github.io/website/ mahdieh@knoesis.org

Current Location: Dayton, Ohio, USA

Personal Statement

I am a PhD candidate of computer science and a graduate research assistant working on machine learning and soft computing techniques. Through several theoretical and applied projects, I have explored various concepts from computer networks and Web mining to machine learning and anomaly detection. I am particularly interested in machine learning for web systems security and web systems characterization, measurements, and analytics.

Education

Ph.D., Computer Science (GPA:4.0)

2017-Present Wright State University, Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Dayton, Ohio, USA

Advisor: Dr. Derek Doran

Focus: Machine learning, web systems characterization, measurement, and analytics

M.S., Computer Engineering-Software (GPA:4.0)

2012-2014

Imam Reza Intl. University, Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, Iran

Advisor: Dr. Majid Vafaei Jahan

Thesis: A Proposed Algorithm Based on Markov Clustering for Web Robot Detection

Focus: Evolutionary computation and optimization methods, soft computing

B.S., Computer Engineering-Software

2007-2011

Ferdowsi University, Dept. of Computer Engineering, Iran

Advisor: Dr. Mohsen Kahani

Thesis: Designing and Implementing a Web-based Account Framework

Focus: Computer networks, web programming, database design & development

Honors and Awards

• Anita Borg Scholar at Grace Hopper, Houston, Texas	2018
• CRA-W Grad Cohort Scholar, San Francisco, California	2018
• Top M.Sc. Software Engineering student researcher, Dept. of Computer and Information	2017
Technology, Intl. University of Imam Reza	
• Best paper award, "Detection of Web site visitors based on fuzzy rough sets", Dept. of Computer	2016
and Information Technology, Intl. University of Imam Reza	
• Top 2 of graduating M.Sc., Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, Intl. University of	2014
Imam Reza	
• Ranked 2 nd in <i>Nationwide</i> Azad university entrance exam for graduate studies	2011
• Ranked in top 1% (among over 300,000 students) in Iranian National University entrance exam	2006

Research Experience

Wright State University, Dayton, Ohio, USA

Graduate Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering Advisor: Dr. Derek Doran

2017-Present

- Topic modeling, content evaluation, and structural analysis of Tor
 - o Related technologies: PhantomJS, NodeJS, SPARQL, R
- Machine learning and soft computing techniques in web agent detection
 - o Related technologies: MATLAB, Python
- Web robot traffic characterization
 - o Related technologies: R, Python, JavaScript

Imam Reza International University, Mashhad, Iran

2014-2016

Dept. of Computer and Information Technology

Advisor: Dr. Majid Vafaei Jahan

- Soft computing and Evolutionary computing techniques in web robot detection
 - Related technologies: MATLAB
- Markov processes with focus on Markov Clustering algorithm
 - o Related technologies: Java, MATLAB
- Using Fuzzy Inference System based on decision trees as web visitor classification
 - Related technologies: Weka, JavaScript, MATLAB

Publications

- M. Zabihimayvan, D. Doran (2019), "Fuzzy Rough Set Feature Selection to Enhance Phishing Attack Detection", IEEE Conference on Fuzzy Systems (Accepted).
- M. Zabihimayyan, Reza Sadeghi, D. Doran, Mehdi Allahyari (2019), "A Broad Evaluation of the Tor English Content Ecosystem", The Web Science Conference (Accepted).
- M. Zabihimayvan, D. Doran (2018), "Some (Non-)Universal Features of Web Robot Traffic", 52th Annual Conference on Information Sciences and Systems (CISS), IEEE, Princeton University, NJ, US.
- M. Zabihimayvan, R. Sadeghi, N. Rude, D. Doran (2017), "A Soft Computing Approach for Benign and Malicious Web Robot Detection", Expert Systems with applications, 87, 129-140, (Impact factor: 3.928).
- J. Hamidzadeh, M. Zabihimayvan, R. Sadeghi (2017), "Detection of Web site visitors based on fuzzy rough sets", Soft Computing, 22(7), 2175-2188, (Impact factor: 2.472).
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "A Density Based Clustering Approach for Web Robot Detection," The 4th International IEEE conference on Computer and knowledge Engineering, IEEE, (Accept Rate: 22%).
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "A density based clustering approach to distinguish between web robot and human requests to a web server," The ISC International Journal of Information Security, 6(1), 77-89.
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "Fuzzy Inference for Intrusion Detection of Web Robots in Computer Networks," 45th Annual Iranian Mathematics Conference, In Persian.
- M. Zabihimayyan, M. Vafaei Jahan (2014), "An Optimum Markov Clustering Algorithm for Accurate Web Robots Detection," The 7th International Conference of Iranian Operations Research Society, In Persian.

M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan (2013), "Web Robot Detection with Fuzzy Inference System Based on Decision Trees," The Seventh International Iranian Data Mining Conference, In Persian.

Patent

M. Zabihimayvan, R. Sadeghi, D. Doran (2018), "Soft Computing Methods for Feature Selection for Web Agent Detection", June 2018, U.S. Provisional Patent, Pending.

Teaching Experience

Wright State University, Dayton, Ohio, US

Sept-Dec 2018

Graduate Teaching Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering

- Introduction on Software Engineering
 - o Developing mobile applications using Xcode and Android Studio IDE

Imam Reza International University, Iran

2012-2014

Graduate Teaching Assistant, Dept. of Computer and Information Technology

- Data mining (graduate course)
 - o Teaching data mining tools in MATLAB and Weka
- Advanced engineering mathematics in software engineering (graduate course)
 - o Statistical analysis and tests, random number generations, finite Markov chain and its algorithmic application
- Computer performance evaluation and modeling (graduate course)
 - o Queueing networks and Markov chains, Markov processes for stochastic modeling, test functions for optimization, Fuzzy control of queueing system, hidden Markov model
- Algorithm design
 - o Time complexity of algorithms, recursion equations, sort algorithms, dynamic programming

Working Experience

Ferdowsi University, Iran

2011-2012

Information and Communication Center, Network & Web developing Group

- Web programming (PHP, CSS, JavaScript, HTML)
- Network management and Security

Mashhad University of Medical Science (MUMS), Iran

2009

Information Technology Center, Web Designing Group

- Web programming (CSS, HTML) and designing websites
- Working with content management systems based on Microsoft SharePoint

Technical Qualifications

Database Programming: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, SPARQL

Programming Language: Python, R, MATLAB, Java, JavaScript, NodeJS, PhantomJS, PHP, CSS, HTML

Data Mining Tools: MATLAB, Python, R

Research service

- Invited talk at the OCWiC conference 2019
- Editorial member of Science Publications
- Journal referee at Computers and Security
- Journal referee at IEEE Transactions on Fuzzy Systems
- Technical Program Committee member of the Web Conference 2018
- Technical Program Committee member of Intelligent Systems Conference 2019
- Technical Program Committee member of Computing Conference 2019
- Technical Program Committee member of International Conference on Computer Science, Engineering and Information Technology 2019